

Saumitra Mazumder



SAMazumder



SAMazumder

About Me ———

Experience with Capital Markets and Market Risk, model development and model validation/audit at a major financial institution. Knowledge of quantitative methodologies in market risk. Thorough and analytical; able to applying logic to solve problems. Excellent verbal and written communication skills. Proven ability to collaborate effectively with diverse individuals and strengthen relationships to achieve well-designed solutions.

Education ———

M.Sc. Applied Mathematics **Ryerson University** 2020-2022 (Expected) Ryerson Graduate Fellowship, Graduate Development Award, Mathematics Graduate Award

B.Sc. Mathematics and Economics Ryerson University 2015-2019 Dean's List 2016, 2017 Ryerson Barbell Club, Ryerson Math Problem Solving Club

Knowledge

Financial Mathematics

Financial Time Series Analysis, Risk Measures, Portfolio Optimization Techniques, Derivative Pricing.

Tools

R, MATLAB, Bloomberg, Stata, Java, Python (SciPy, NumPy, PANDAS, OOP, XGBoost), Machine Learning, LaTeX, Microsoft Word, Microsoft

Excel, Microsoft PowerPoint, C++, C and SQL

Employment History

2022-Current Scotiabank

Velocity Intern - Audit, Retail Credit Risk.

Member of the team auditing ECL models (PD, CCI, EAD, LGD) per IFRS 9 guidance provided by OSFI. Used internal audit methodol-

ogy to provide independent oversight of models.

Closed audit issues pertaining an end-to-end retail model proce-

dure.

2018-Current Ryerson University, Department of Mathematics

Graduate Research Assistant under Dr. Foivos Xanthos

Completed research in Functional Analysis and its use in coherent risk measures on L^p -spaces.

Developed empirical algorithms to implement general-moment mar-

ket risk measures

Analyzed financial data using non-parametric methods to demon-

strate the potential benefits of general-moment models.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

Lead tutorials for graduate and undergraduate courses. Marking and

test invigilation for assigned courses.

Coached diverse group of students to become familiar with fundamental and advanced statistical concepts like MLE estimation, hypothesis testing, linear and non-linear regression models and solv-

ing various statistical problems using R.

Undergraduate Research Assistant under Dr. Foivos Xanthos

Completed research on time series, probability theory, functional

analysis and their applications to financial instruments.

2012-2020

Sylvan Learning Centres, Mentor's Academy and The Academy for

Mathematics & English

Tutor specializing in mathematics, chemistry, biology and physics. Provided tutoring services to various centres across the greater

Toronto Area.

Major Projects

Graduate Thesis

Extending Coherent Risk Measures to Orlicz spaces (tentative)

When estimating the risk of a P&L from historical data or Monte Carlo simulation, the robustness of the estimate is important. Analyzed a refined notion of robustness that applies to tail-dependent law-

invariant convex risk measures on Orlicz spaces

Graduate Project

An Analyst's Exposition of "Comparative and Qualitative Robustness

for Law-invariant Risk Measures"

A presentation giving a functional analytic exposition of the work of Kraätschmer, Schied and Zähle up to Theorem 2.6.

Undergraduate An Extreme Value Analysis of Financial Time Series

Thesis

A study of extreme movements in financial asset returns. Showed that asset returns will have extreme realizations with greater probability than predicted by Black-Scholes model. Modelled the probability of extreme movements using Extreme Value Theory.